[
  {
    "question": "A publisher printed 50,000 copies of a book. All but 500 copies were sold. Of the books sold,",
    "choices": [
      "0 percent were sold at half price, and the remaining copies were sold at the full price of $20. <br>What was the publisher's total revenue?",
      "$859500",
      "$940500",
      "$950000",
      "$999500"
    ],
    "answer": "B",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/a-publisher-printed-50-000-copies-of-a-book-all-but-500-copies-were-s-226623.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many gallons of milk that is 10 percent butter-fat must be added to 8 gallons of milk that is 35 percent butterfat to obtain milk that is 20 percent butterfat?",
    "choices": [
      "6",
      "12",
      "14",
      "16",
      "28"
    ],
    "answer": "B",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/how-many-gallons-of-milk-that-is-10-percent-butter-fat-must-159068.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "An empty fuel tank with a capacity of 200 gallons was filled partially with fuel A and then to capacity with fuel B. Fuel A contains 12% ethanol by volume and fuel B contains 16% ethanol by volume. If the full fuel tank contains 30 gallons of ethanol, how many gallons of fuel A were added?<br>",
    "choices": [
      "160",
      "150",
      "100",
      "80",
      "50"
    ],
    "answer": "E",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/an-empty-fuel-tank-with-a-capacity-of-200-gallons-was-fill-133301.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "Solution A has 5% salt concentration and remaining water. After heating 50 litres of Solution A at a certain temperature, due to evaporation, the salt concentration increases to 10%. The amount of water remaining in the solution would be",
    "choices": [
      "30 litres",
      "27 litres",
      "25 litres",
      "22.5 litres",
      "20 litres"
    ],
    "answer": "D",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/solution-a-has-5-salt-concentration-and-remaining-water-after-heatin-189491.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "When 20% of a solution of milk and water is removed and replaced with water, the ratio of milk and water becomes 2 : 3. Find the ratio of milk and water in the original solution.",
    "choices": [
      "1 : 1",
      "1 : 2 ",
      "2 : 1 ",
      "1 : 3",
      "3 : 2"
    ],
    "answer": "A",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/when-20-of-a-solution-of-milk-and-water-is-removed-and-replaced-with-293326.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "15 lts are taken of from a container full of liquid A and replaced with Liquid B. Again 15 more lts of the mixture is taken and replaced with liquid B. After this process, if the container contains Liquid A and B in the ratio 9:16,What is the capacity of the container?<br>",
    "choices": [
      "45",
      "25",
      "37.5",
      "36",
      "42"
    ],
    "answer": "C",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/15-lts-are-taken-of-from-a-container-full-of-liquid-a-and-replaced-wit-121276.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two containers of equal capacity are full of a mixture  of oil and water . In the first, the ratio of oil to water is 4:7 and in the second it is 7:11. Now both the mixtures are mixed in a bigger container. What is the resulting ratio of oil to water.",
    "choices": [
      "149 : 247",
      "247 : 149",
      "143 : 241",
      "241 : 143",
      null
    ],
    "answer": "A",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/two-containers-of-equal-capacity-are-full-of-a-mixture-of-oil-and-wat-113800.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "Drinks A and B are mixtures of lemon and orange juices. The ratio of lemon to orange juice is 1:3 in drink A. In drink B, the ratio of lemon to orange juices is 5 : 3. If drink A is mixed with drink B to form drink C in the ratio of 4 : 1, what is the ratio of lemon to orange juice in drink c?",
    "choices": [
      "1 : 1",
      "2 : 1",
      "3 : 2",
      "13 : 27",
      "15 : 19"
    ],
    "answer": "D",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/drinks-a-and-b-are-mixtures-of-lemon-and-orange-juices-the-ratio-of-l-277272.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sue's trail mix is 30% nuts and 70% dried fruit. Jane's trail mix is 60% nuts and 40% chocolate chips. If the combined mixture of Sue and Jane's trails mix contains 50% nuts, what percent of the combined mixture is dried fruit?",
    "choices": [
      "16.67%",
      "23.33%",
      "25%",
      "33.33%",
      "36.67%"
    ],
    "answer": "B",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/sue-s-trail-mix-is-30-nuts-and-70-dried-fruit-jane-s-trai-169998.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "If Adrian mixes 15 liters of saline solution A with 5 liters of a 40% saline solution to get a 25% saline solution, what percent saline is solution A ?",
    "choices": [
      "5",
      "10",
      "15",
      "20",
      "25"
    ],
    "answer": "D",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/if-adrian-mixes-15-liters-of-saline-solution-a-with-5-liters-of-a-256424.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "A snack mix that is 20% raisins is blended with a second mix that is 30% raisins. The initial blend is 5 pounds of the first mix and 10 pound of the second. To make the final blend 22% raisins, how many additional pounds of the first mix must be added to the initial blend?",
    "choices": [
      "- 25",
      "- 30",
      "- 35",
      "- 40",
      "- 50"
    ],
    "answer": "C",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/a-snack-mix-that-is-20-raisins-is-blended-with-a-second-mix-that-is-232402.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "A milk vendor has 2 cans of milk. The first contains 25% water and the rest milk. The second contains 50% water. How much milk should he mix from each of the containers so as to get 12 litres of milk such that the ratio of water to milk is 3 : 5?",
    "choices": [
      "\t4 litres, 8 litres",
      "\t6 litres, 6 litres",
      "\t5 litres, 7 litres",
      "\t7 litres, 5 litres",
      "8 litres, 7litres"
    ],
    "answer": "B",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/a-milk-vendor-has-2-cans-of-milk-the-first-contains-25-water-and-the-288033.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "To a solution having milk and water in the ratio 2 : 3, 15 lts of water is added and then 15 lts of the solution is drawn out. This operation is done a total of thrice. If the ratio of milk and water now is 25 : 231, find the volume of original solution.",
    "choices": [
      "25 lts",
      "30 lts ",
      "40 lts ",
      "45 lts",
      "60 lts"
    ],
    "answer": "A",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/to-a-solution-having-milk-and-water-in-the-ratio-2-3-15-lts-of-wate-292584.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "A milkman mixes 20 litres of water with 80 litres of milk. After selling one-fourth of this mixture, he adds water to replenish the quantity that he had sold. What is the current proportion of water to milk?",
    "choices": [
      "2:3",
      "1:2",
      "1:3",
      "3:4",
      "1:1"
    ],
    "answer": "A",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/a-milkman-mixes-20-litres-of-water-with-80-litres-of-milk-280517.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a milkman wishes to earn a profit of 16.66% by selling milk at cost price and mixing water to the milk. What percent of the mixture has to be water?",
    "choices": [
      "12.5",
      "14.28",
      "20",
      "25",
      "35"
    ],
    "answer": "B",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/if-a-milkman-wishes-to-earn-a-profit-of-16-66-by-selling-milk-at-cost-285347.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "10kg of a mixture contains 30% sand and 70% clay. In order to make the mixture contain equal quantities of clay and sand how much of the mixture is to be removed and replaced with pure sand?",
    "choices": [],
    "answer": "20/7",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/gmat-question-of-the-day-latest-edition-239951.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mixture X contains 60% water and 40% chloride. If 120 gallons of Mixture Y is added to 80 gallons of mixture X in order to produce a solution that contains 75% water and 25% chloride, how many gallons of water must mixture Y contain?",
    "choices": [],
    "answer": "there are 72 gal of water and 48 gal of chloride in mixture X",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/mixture-x-contains-60-water-and-40-chloride-if-120-gallon-105688.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "A and B are two alloys of copper and tin prepared by mixing the respective metals in ratio of 5:3 and 5:11 respectively. If the alloy A and B are mixed to form a third alloy C with an equal proportions of copper and tin what is the ration of alloys A and B In the new alloy C?",
    "choices": [
      "3:5",
      "4:5",
      "3:2",
      "2:3",
      "15:17"
    ],
    "answer": "C",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/a-and-b-are-two-alloys-of-copper-and-tin-prepared-by-mixing-the-respec-302621.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ratio of alcohol and water in three mixtures of alcohol and water is 3:2, 4:1, and 7:3. If equal quantities of the mixture are drawn and mixed, the concentration of alcohol in the resulting mixture will be?",
    "choices": [
      "65%",
      "70%",
      "75%",
      "80%",
      null
    ],
    "answer": "B",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/the-ratio-of-alcohol-and-water-in-three-mixtures-of-alcohol-and-water-213314.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "A 30-litre bucket contains a mixture of milk and water in the ratio 2:1. A certain quantity of this mixture is replaced by water such that the ratio of milk and water becomes 8:7. This resultant mixture is added to 20 litres of another mixture containing milk and water in the ratio 3:1. What is the percentage of milk in the new mixture?",
    "choices": [
      "75%",
      "53%",
      "45%",
      "62%",
      "58%"
    ],
    "answer": "D",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/a-30-litre-bucket-contains-a-mixture-of-milk-and-water-in-the-ratio-292628.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fresh dates contain 90% water while dry dates contain 28% water . How many kg of dry dates can be obtained from 36kg of fresh dates ?",
    "choices": [
      "5Kg",
      "10Kg",
      "12 Kg",
      "6Kg",
      null
    ],
    "answer": "A",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/fresh-dates-contain-90-water-while-dry-dates-contain-143245.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "A mixture of 240 liters contains milk and water in the ratio of 5 : 3. A milkman mixes some more water in it and claim to sell it at cost price. If cost price of pure milk is Rs. 20/liter and water is freely available and milkman made a total profit of 80% on cost price of pure milk then find amount of water he mixed in the milk.",
    "choices": [
      "20 liters",
      "30 liters",
      "35 liters",
      "40 liters",
      "45 liters"
    ],
    "answer": "B",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/a-mixture-of-240-liters-contains-milk-and-water-in-the-ratio-of-319512.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two-fifth of the cars manufactured by a company are defective. Three-fifth of the defective cars and one-twentieth of the non-defective cars are left hand drive. If all the left hand drive cars are exported by the factory and every car manufactured is either left hand drive or right hand drive, then what fraction of exported left hand cars are defective?",
    "choices": [
      "6/25",
      "8/9",
      "3/5",
      "1/9",
      null
    ],
    "answer": "B",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/two-fifth-of-the-cars-manufactured-venn-diagram-274967.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "A milkman mixes water and milk in a container in the ratio of 2 : 5, respectively. Initially, he sells the mixture at $30 per liter. After selling 70 liters of mixture, he mixes another 20 liters of water and then ratio of water and milk becomes 8 : 15, respectively. The new mixture is sold by the milk man at the rate of $25 per liter. If cost of milk is $27 per liter then find the profit of milkman in the whole transaction?",
    "choices": [
      "$2050",
      "$2500",
      "$2950",
      "$2450",
      "$3300"
    ],
    "answer": "D",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/a-milkman-mixes-water-and-milk-in-a-container-in-the-ratio-291555.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "12.5% of a solution having milk and water in the ratio 24 : 25 is removed and replaced with water. Find the ratio of milk and water in the solution if this operation is done a total of three times.",
    "choices": [
      "21 : 64",
      "27 : 64",
      "8 : 27",
      "27 : 33",
      "21 : 43"
    ],
    "answer": "E",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/12-5-of-a-solution-having-milk-and-water-in-the-ratio-24-25-is-remo-289617.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "From a 3 : 5 solution of milk and water, 20% is taken out and replaced by milk. How many times should this process be done to make the ratio of milk to water as 17 : 8?",
    "choices": [
      "Once",
      "Twice",
      "Thrice",
      "Four times",
      "Five times"
    ],
    "answer": "C",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/from-a-3-5-solution-of-milk-and-water-20-is-taken-out-and-replaced-323949.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Container contains \u2018X\u2019 Liters of Milk. A thief stole 50 Liters of Milk and replaced it with the same quantity of water. He repeated the same process further two times. And thus Milk in the container is only \u2018X-122\u2019 liters. Then what is the quantity of water in the final mixture?",
    "choices": [
      "250 Liter",
      "124 Liter",
      "128 Liter",
      "122 Liter",
      "150 liter"
    ],
    "answer": "D",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/a-container-contains-x-liters-of-milk-a-thief-stole-293646.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "A chemistry student is working with solution M, which has a 20% calcium chloride concentration. He needs to remove three-fourths of this solution and then add a new solution, solution N, to create a third solution, solution P, with double the volume of solution M. What must the calcium chloride concentration of solution N be to create a calcium chloride concentration of 37.5% in solution P?",
    "choices": [
      "32%",
      "35%",
      "40%",
      "44%",
      null
    ],
    "answer": "C",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/a-chemistry-student-is-working-with-solution-m-which-has-a-20-calciu-270403.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "A wholesaler bought walnuts and peanuts, the price of walnut per kg being thrice that of peanut per kg. He then sold 8 kg of peanuts at a profit of 10% and 16 kg of walnuts at a profit of 20% to a shopkeeper. However, the shopkeeper lost 5 kg of walnuts and 3 kg of peanuts in transit. He then mixed the remaining nuts and sold the mixture at $166 per kg, thus making an overall profit of 25%. At what price, in $ per kg, did the wholesaler buy the walnuts? ",
    "choices": [
      "84",
      "86",
      "88",
      "96",
      "98"
    ],
    "answer": "A",
    "link": "https://gmatclub.com/forum/a-wholesaler-bought-walnuts-and-peanuts-the-price-of-walnut-per-kg-be-320224.html"
  }
]